<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>orange on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/orange/</link>
    <description>Recent content in orange on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 20:45:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/orange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Orange Roll</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-09-orange-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 20:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-09-orange-roll/</guid>
      <description>An orange roll has very few ingredients and no flour at all. It might sound strange but this specific kind of roll doesn&#39;t need it. There are a lot of different kinds of rolls and it is a rather common dessert in Portugal. It is fresh and light. This is my mum&#39;s recipe which I think is better than the one from Pantagruel (the only difference is in the quantity used).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange &amp; Ginger Chicken Thighs</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 22:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and this was the first time that I gave it a try. The fresh ginger got my attention, but I have to say that it doesn&#39;t sound, or taste, very Portuguese. Nonetheless, it was very tasty and the mixture of orange and ginger resulted in a remarkably fresh aroma, making this recipe perfect for a summer day.Ingredients (3 servings) 6 chicken thighs and/or whole legs 1dl white wine 1 tablespoon vegetable oil 1/2 tablespoon fresh grated ginger zest 1 orange fresh mint leaves salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Sponge Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 09:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned on a post about the chocolate mousse that I know three dessert recipes by heart. I&#39;ve shared the pancake recipe, the chocolate mousse and now it&#39;s time for the Sponge Cake. This time I decided to make an Orange Sponge Cake, but you can use the zest of a lemon instead of a zest of an orange. In my family, we make this cake regularly for guests or to take with us to my grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
