<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 11:15:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Seoul</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2013-04-09-a-trip-to-seoul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 10:59:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2013-04-09-a-trip-to-seoul/</guid>
      <description>The husband got a chance to travel to South Korea in a business trip this past week and I was lucky enough to tag along. We spent 6 days in Seoul and it was a wonderful experience. I loved their food and here are some photos I took.
Our first meal in Seoul was a great start. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of the restaurant though. We sat on the floor, shoes off and had an amazing Korean barbecue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing 2012</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2013-01-08-closing-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 14:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2013-01-08-closing-2012/</guid>
      <description>I probably should have posted this two weeks ago, but even if I&amp;rsquo;m a little late to the party, I think I could not not show you our Christmas Eve table that my mother-in-law put together. We consumed copious amounts of amazing food in great company. I can only imagine a better setting if my sister had spent Christmas Eve with us. Here it goes. And check out my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s dinnerware!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year!</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2013-01-01-happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2013-01-01-happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-12-24-merry-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 17:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-12-24-merry-christmas/</guid>
      <description>So here I am to finally wish you a Merry Christmas.
I had hoped I could should you some Christmas lights, but this year there are none to be found in Leiria. There was however a very sunny day this week.
And a fluffy kitten.
Some rice pudding in the making.
Coscorões - recipe to come.
And Bolo Rei!
Have a good Christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation - Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-09-09-vacation-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 10:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-09-09-vacation-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the vacation segment, close to Leiria we have plenty of beaches to choose from. For some reason, many of my friends and family spent their childhood summers at Pedrogão. The beach isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly beautiful when compared with other beaches in the region, and the weather and the sea are extremely unpredictable. However, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of sand, good fresh fish and when the weather is nice, you kind of forget how bad it was just the day before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation - Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-09-07-vacation-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 13:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-09-07-vacation-part-i/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been absent for a couple of weeks but for good reason. I went to Portugal on vacation and, as always, it takes me a while to want to post afterwards. But here it is. We grew up in Leiria, but ever since we moved to Denmark, we kind of treat it like we&amp;rsquo;re tourists. A lot of walking around and a lot of photos. Leiria is especially known for its food, so I decided to document some of the stuff that I ate there, as well as the beautiful surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-06-25-traveling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-06-25-traveling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry for the little hiatus. We went to Portugal and then to Sweden for Dreamhack. Unfortunately, I forgot my camera&amp;rsquo;s SD card in Portugal and as such I only have photos of Portugal from my cellphone. But here we go:
Walked a bit around Leiria during the day.
And at night too.
Hung out with my cat.
Baked an orange sponge cake to take to my grandparents. Shared Mille-feuilles with my sister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-04-27-im-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 15:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-04-27-im-back/</guid>
      <description>Well that took longer than I expected. But I&amp;rsquo;m back and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll resume the regular posting, starting with a belated Easter recipe. In the meanwhile, here is a photo of my old kitchen and a photo of the new one.
Quite the upgrade, if I may say so myself! :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll be back in two weeks (?)</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-03-31-ill-be-back-in-two-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 13:31:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-03-31-ill-be-back-in-two-weeks/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re moving to a new apartment which means that we&amp;rsquo;ll be without internet access for at least two weeks. ಥ_ಥ 
And this week, I tried out a recipe that just wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough so here is a squirrel:
This little guy was hanging around Hans Christian Andersen&amp;rsquo;s grave (hence the Digteren)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thursday: Cock&#39;s &amp; Cows</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-03-29-random-thursday-cocks-cows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 12:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-03-29-random-thursday-cocks-cows/</guid>
      <description>Spring has definitely arrived to Denmark. A friend of ours came to visit which meant a lot of walking and the obligatory visit to Halifax. In Copenhagen, when it starts to get warm, everyone goes outside and sit under the sun for any other purpose than to enjoy the nice weather. And after living here for a while I can understand why.
We went to Halifax the first day and on the second day we decided to show our friend another awesome restaurant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thursday: Denmark 2</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-03-02-random-thursday-denmark-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 17:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-03-02-random-thursday-denmark-2/</guid>
      <description>More like Friday I know. I have mentioned before that I have a Diana F+ (120mm) and that the husband has an Holga (35mm). This means that occasionally we need to develop film. Yesterday was one of those days, hence the delay in this post.
When we moved here, we came across a great store called Photografica. If you ever need to develop film or buy a camera (new or used), in Copenhagen, this is the place to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Delicacies</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-02-23-portuguese-delicacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 12:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-02-23-portuguese-delicacies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a word for what happened at our place last week but I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there&amp;rsquo;s an equivalent in english to petisco. A petisco is when you create a spread of food that can be cooked or not and that is usually eaten outside of traditional meal times. We started at 4pm. You slowly pick bits of this and that, along with your drink of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Valentine&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-02-14-happy-valentines-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 10:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-02-14-happy-valentines-day/</guid>
      <description>As seen on Petite Kitchenesse. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thursday: Denmark</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-02-09-random-thursday-denmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 12:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-02-09-random-thursday-denmark/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my first Random Thursday. This space will be dedicated to any kind of topic that I feel like writing about/show the world that doesn&amp;rsquo;t include a recipe. I think that it might be a good idea to explain why there is a photo of a burger in the slide show! The burger in the photo is in my opinion the best burger in Copenhagen. It also happens to be available in the best burger place in the city: Halifax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-01-19-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 09:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/life/2012-01-19-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
It&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and I&amp;rsquo;m about to leave for the gym. Still don&amp;rsquo;t know what to cook Saturday. One of the things that bugs me the most about living in Denmark is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find Portuguese ingredients that are crucial for some recipes. And that it&amp;rsquo;s way my recipes won&amp;rsquo;t be all of Portuguese origin. We do go to Portugal every 3 months, give or take, which means that we can bring with us some &amp;ldquo;chouriço&amp;rdquo; or even some &amp;ldquo;bacalhau&amp;rdquo; (cod fish).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
