<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>breakfast on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/courses/breakfast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in breakfast on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 16:04:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/courses/breakfast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Tarts</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-06-11-apple-tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 16:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-06-11-apple-tarts/</guid>
      <description>So it has been a while! And here I am with probably the longest post so far. But for a very good reason: a new and improved puff pastry for tarts recipe (here is the old one) and some delicious apple tarts. The husband loves these tarts. We had some the last time we were in Portugal, which naturally prompted me to answer the question: can I make this at home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread II</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</guid>
      <description>I hope you&#39;re having a nice Easter. Last year I shared a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34; for a traditional Portuguese Easter bread, but I completely failed its presentation. So this year I decided to try a new recipe and this time from &#34;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&#34;. And I&#39;m glad I decided to give it a try because I actually prefer this version. The egg in the middle is completely optional. I&amp;rsquo;ve never in my life ate the boiled egg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentine&#39;s Day Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-02-07-valentines-day-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 16:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-02-07-valentines-day-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Valentine&#39;s Day is almost here and I just had to make something in the shape of an heart. Last year was breakfast, but this year I made cinnamon cookies. Last Christmas I got a classic Portuguese cookbook called &amp;ldquo;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&amp;rdquo; by Maria de Lourdes Modesto. It has amazing detailed recipes from all over the country and it even has some pictures (as opposed to Pantagruel). This is the third recipe that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried from this book and it turned out even better than I was expecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filhoses</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-12-filhoses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 15:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-12-filhoses/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve shared a recipe for bacalhau (salted and dried codfish), but no Portuguese Christmas dinner is complete without filhoses (or velhoses). Or at least this is true for Center Portugal. Filhoses can be made of pumpkin or of carrots. In my family however we only make carrot filhoses. Both my grandmothers use carrots and this is the recipe of one of them. They never really measured their ingredients, but this is a close approximation that an aunt of mine came up with, after watching my grandmother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic White Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-26-basic-white-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 13:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-26-basic-white-bread/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with a bread recipe for two months now. Since we only eat bread on our cheat day (we&#39;re on paleo), it took a while to get it to where I wanted it to. Bread in Denmark is remarkably different from the bread in Portugal and we find ourselves craving for something authentic, from time to time. A few years ago, my dad gave me a recipe for bread that could be tweaked to what I was looking for in a loaf of bread, with a range of possible percentages for flour and yeast instead of quantities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broas do Bolinho</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 14:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</guid>
      <description>Now this is a first. I couldn&#39;t find an appropriate title in English for this post so there you go, good old Portuguese. We don&#39;t really celebrate Halloween in Portugal. Instead, on the 1st of November, children wake up early in the morning and go door-to-door asking for Bolinho or Pão-por-Deus - basically they get treats that can be in the form of these rolls I&#39;m sharing today, chocolates, money or even walnuts/chestnuts if you&#39;re terribly unlucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot Walnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-22-carrot-walnut-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 13:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-22-carrot-walnut-cake/</guid>
      <description>And now for a very simple but delicious cake. The cake&#39;s recipe is from an aunt of mine and I decided to spruce it up a bit with an orange glaze. &#34;Pantagruel&#34; has several recipes for glazes, and orange+carrot seemed a great combo. It was. On a side note, can you tell that the light in Denmark has already started to change? From now until April I guess I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to start prepping dinner at 2pm if I want to shoot with natural light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chouriço Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 16:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</guid>
      <description>Chouriço Bread, or Pão com Chouriço as we call it, is a treat you can find in Portuguese markets and fairs. It&#39;s usually baked in a trailer with wood fired ovens. You can also find it year-round in supermarkets, cafes or, more specifically, in Lisbon at Merendeira. There are even places that serve not only chouriço bread, but dried codfish bread, black pudding bread and pork rind bread. Good stuff. The recipe for the bread dough can also be used for baking regular bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Birthday Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 23:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</guid>
      <description>Every since I can remember, all birthdays in my family are celebrated with this cake. There is no real reason not to make it for other occasions, but I can&#39;t help but feel that it is a birthday type of cake. It also helps that my birthday is in July and that I get to use really good strawberries. It&#39;s my favorite cake without a doubt. If you don&#39;t like wet cakes, skip the part where I use the juice of one orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Egg Tarts - Pastel de Nata (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-10-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 22:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-10-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Now for part II of the Portuguese Egg Tarts. As I mentioned before, I used store-bought puff pastry when I tried the egg tarts recipe for the first time. I promised a recipe for puff pastry and here it is. But I have to say that I was a little disappointed with the result. I was excepting it to be great but the texture wasn&#39;t 100% right. The flavor however surpassed the store-bought puff pastry without a doubt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Egg Tarts - Pastel de Nata (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-03-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 13:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-03-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-i/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been wanting to try a Pastel de Nata recipe for years now. Pantagruel has two recipes, I tried them both and they were kind of bad... The taste was o.k. but the texture was nothing like the real deal. Who knows, maybe in the old days that&#39;s how they did it. Then I remembered that a aunt of mine used to bring a Portuguese egg tart (a whole tart) to my grandparents and thought that it might be worth a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey &amp; Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 13:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>And now for another surprisingly good cookies that include olive oil in the recipe (like the Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake). The husband wanted to take some cookies with him to a competition and I usually bake lemon cookies and something else. These were a perfect addition. The recipe is from Pantagruel and it included an alcoholic Portuguese beverage called Aguardentewhich I didn&#39;t include because I don&#39;t like desserts with alcohol. But if you do, just add 9 tablespoons (or 1 cálice if you have any idea what I&#39;m talking about).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinnamon Rolls</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-24-cinnamon-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 11:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-24-cinnamon-rolls/</guid>
      <description>The first time I visited Denmark, I tried their Cinnamon Rolls from some bakery and I have to say that I wasn&#39;t impressed. I also tried the store bought ones and although I liked them better, I got the feeling that I hadn&#39;t tried the real deal yet. So, when I saw that Aarstiderne had released their recipe on their Facebook page I couldn&#39;t resist giving it a try (Aarstiderne supplies organically produced fruit and vegetables door to door).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the Easter topic, here is a recipe for a traditional Easter bread called *&#34;Folar&#34;*, from Pantagruel. The presentation doesn&#39;t exactly match what you would find in Portugal, but the taste sure does. The traditional presentation includes a baked egg in the middle of the bread (that we actually don&#39;t like). And I happened to forgot to brush the bread with egg yolk. :)Ingredients (2 loaves) 475g (4 cups) flour 190g (6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</guid>
      <description>I looked at this recipe several times before deciding that it might be a good one. The fact that it includes olive oil on the ingredients list threw me off at first, but my curiosity got the better of me and I am grateful for it. It was an exceptional good cake with a lot of flavor and a very soft texture. Yes, it asks for a lot of honey, but in the end it was just the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Bean Tarts</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-20-white-bean-tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 15:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-20-white-bean-tarts/</guid>
      <description>White Bean Tarts are a traditional pastry from central Portugal (where I happen to come from). But you can find this tarts all over the country (Lisbon&#39;s airport included). They&#39;re extremely sweet and taste nothing like beans. They work great for a party or to accompany an espresso for your mid-afternoon snack. This was the first time I used this recipe and it worked out great. Ingredients (12 tarts) 500g (2 1/2 cups) caster sugar 300g (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 10:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll be sharing a recipe from Pantagruel of a common bread substitute for breakfast or a mid-afternoon snack. I don&#39;t have a mixer, so I just did everything by hand, but if you have a mixer it should be a lot easier. The recipe only asks for a small amount of sugar, but it makes all the difference. They should be soft and fluffy.Ingredients (8-10 buns) 300g (2 1/2 cups) flour 70g (1/3 cup) sugar  25g (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Sponge Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 09:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned on a post about the chocolate mousse that I know three dessert recipes by heart. I&#39;ve shared the pancake recipe, the chocolate mousse and now it&#39;s time for the Sponge Cake. This time I decided to make an Orange Sponge Cake, but you can use the zest of a lemon instead of a zest of an orange. In my family, we make this cake regularly for guests or to take with us to my grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantagruel&#39;s Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>And here is another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe and it did not disappoint. I will definitely make this chocolate cake again, but I will change the baking time for the next time I use this one. The recipe asked for 45-50 minutes in the oven and after 30 minutes I checked it with a toothpick and it was done! Ingredients (12 servings) 225g flour (1 cup) (+ a bit for the cake pan) 150g granulated sugar (3/4 cup) 130g butter at room temperature (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Desserts are my favorite things to cook. This recipe has turned out a great success every time I used it. It takes some time to finish but in the end is totally worth it. The husband loves these cookies. They keep well and make a great combo with coffee or tea. And it&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!Ingredients (30 cookies) 1/2kg white flour (4 cups) 200g granulated sugar (7oz) 250g butter at room temperature (9oz) 2 eggs 1 small lemon  Instructions (Time: 2 hours)Start by beating the eggs with the sugar and the zest of the lemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday&#39;s Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-28-saturdays-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 12:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-28-saturdays-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>The best away to celebrate our day off is to start the day with our favorite breakfast: Pancakes! We&#39;ve been eating pancakes on Saturdays ever since we moved to Denmark. It&#39;s easy to make and we never get tired of it. With some butter and maple syrup, a cup of coffee and orange juice... Saturdays are the best! Ingredients (2-3 servings) 1 egg 250mL milk (or 1 cup) 120g flour (1 cup) 1 tablespoon granulated sugar 1/3 teaspoon salt 2 heaped teaspoons baking powder  2 tablespoons vegetable oil or melted butter  butter and maple syrup to taste  (Note: You can just use the same measuring instrument you used for the milk to measure the flour, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a measuring cup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
