<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 18:27:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Tarts</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-06-11-apple-tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 16:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-06-11-apple-tarts/</guid>
      <description>So it has been a while! And here I am with probably the longest post so far. But for a very good reason: a new and improved puff pastry for tarts recipe (here is the old one) and some delicious apple tarts. The husband loves these tarts. We had some the last time we were in Portugal, which naturally prompted me to answer the question: can I make this at home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Seoul</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2013-04-09-a-trip-to-seoul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 10:59:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2013-04-09-a-trip-to-seoul/</guid>
      <description>The husband got a chance to travel to South Korea in a business trip this past week and I was lucky enough to tag along. We spent 6 days in Seoul and it was a wonderful experience. I loved their food and here are some photos I took.
Our first meal in Seoul was a great start. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name of the restaurant though. We sat on the floor, shoes off and had an amazing Korean barbecue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread II</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</guid>
      <description>I hope you&#39;re having a nice Easter. Last year I shared a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34; for a traditional Portuguese Easter bread, but I completely failed its presentation. So this year I decided to try a new recipe and this time from &#34;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&#34;. And I&#39;m glad I decided to give it a try because I actually prefer this version. The egg in the middle is completely optional. I&amp;rsquo;ve never in my life ate the boiled egg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Pork Carré</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-17-roasted-pork-carre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-17-roasted-pork-carre/</guid>
      <description>I grew up eating pork carré occasionally and was truly surprised when I found this meat cut here in Denmark, even though carré doesn&#39;t sound Portuguese at all. And with a recognizable name! (Svine carré). I made some changes to a recipe from Culinária Portuguese and it worked perfectly. It is a moist pork roast and I think the fat on top helps to give it flavor. This recipe followed a series of mishaps in the last month, so I was more than happy with how wonderful this roast turned out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond Squares</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-02-25-almond-squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 20:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-02-25-almond-squares/</guid>
      <description>Almond Tart is a staple at my grandparents for every party/celebration. The recipe that my aunts use is more of a cake than a tart. But I wanted to try something knew and as it turns out a tart base is just as good. This tart contains extraordinary amounts of butter and a crunchy top. It&amp;rsquo;s great on it&amp;rsquo;s own or even better when accompanied by some vanilla ice cream. The recipe is from Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentine&#39;s Day Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-02-07-valentines-day-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 16:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-02-07-valentines-day-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Valentine&#39;s Day is almost here and I just had to make something in the shape of an heart. Last year was breakfast, but this year I made cinnamon cookies. Last Christmas I got a classic Portuguese cookbook called &amp;ldquo;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&amp;rdquo; by Maria de Lourdes Modesto. It has amazing detailed recipes from all over the country and it even has some pictures (as opposed to Pantagruel). This is the third recipe that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried from this book and it turned out even better than I was expecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing 2012</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2013-01-08-closing-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 14:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2013-01-08-closing-2012/</guid>
      <description>I probably should have posted this two weeks ago, but even if I&amp;rsquo;m a little late to the party, I think I could not not show you our Christmas Eve table that my mother-in-law put together. We consumed copious amounts of amazing food in great company. I can only imagine a better setting if my sister had spent Christmas Eve with us. Here it goes. And check out my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s dinnerware!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year!</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2013-01-01-happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2013-01-01-happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-12-24-merry-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 17:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-12-24-merry-christmas/</guid>
      <description>So here I am to finally wish you a Merry Christmas.
I had hoped I could should you some Christmas lights, but this year there are none to be found in Leiria. There was however a very sunny day this week.
And a fluffy kitten.
Some rice pudding in the making.
Coscorões - recipe to come.
And Bolo Rei!
Have a good Christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filhoses</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-12-filhoses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 15:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-12-filhoses/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve shared a recipe for bacalhau (salted and dried codfish), but no Portuguese Christmas dinner is complete without filhoses (or velhoses). Or at least this is true for Center Portugal. Filhoses can be made of pumpkin or of carrots. In my family however we only make carrot filhoses. Both my grandmothers use carrots and this is the recipe of one of them. They never really measured their ingredients, but this is a close approximation that an aunt of mine came up with, after watching my grandmother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacalhau with Broa</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-08-bacalhau-with-broa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 22:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-08-bacalhau-with-broa/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of this Christmas season, here is a recipe worthy of a Christmas dinner in Portugal. Bacalhau, or codfish that has been salted and dried, is commonly eaten on Christmas Eve in Portugal, roasted or boiled accompanied by cabbage or potatoes. My sister and my brother-in-law came to visit us recently and brought us two essential ingredients: bacalhau and broa (a special kind of cornbread). It&#39;s possible to find *bacalhau* in Denmark, but *broa* is nearly impossible, I&#39;d say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic White Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-26-basic-white-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 13:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-26-basic-white-bread/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with a bread recipe for two months now. Since we only eat bread on our cheat day (we&#39;re on paleo), it took a while to get it to where I wanted it to. Bread in Denmark is remarkably different from the bread in Portugal and we find ourselves craving for something authentic, from time to time. A few years ago, my dad gave me a recipe for bread that could be tweaked to what I was looking for in a loaf of bread, with a range of possible percentages for flour and yeast instead of quantities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Flan</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-21-apple-flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 16:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-21-apple-flan/</guid>
      <description>I talked raisins and nuts last week and it wouldn&#39;t be right to skip cooking something with apples this autumn. Whenever I&#39;m out of ideas for new recipes I just pick &#34;Pantagruel&#34; and look for inspiration. This recipe seemed simple enough and, more importantly, the main focus was on apples. The recipe called for Reinetteapples. These apples originated in France and are oftentimes used as a cooking apples in Portugal. Unfortunately, I couldn&#39;t find them in Denmark and so I used Royal Gala instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broas do Bolinho</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 14:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</guid>
      <description>Now this is a first. I couldn&#39;t find an appropriate title in English for this post so there you go, good old Portuguese. We don&#39;t really celebrate Halloween in Portugal. Instead, on the 1st of November, children wake up early in the morning and go door-to-door asking for Bolinho or Pão-por-Deus - basically they get treats that can be in the form of these rolls I&#39;m sharing today, chocolates, money or even walnuts/chestnuts if you&#39;re terribly unlucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Rice Pudding </title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-07-portuguese-rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 13:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-07-portuguese-rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>I keep introducing Portuguese recipes as &#34;classic&#34;/&#34;traditional&#34;, but lets face it, Portuguese Rice Pudding is a Portuguese classic. It&#39;s on our tables at birthday parties, Christmas and any other occasion. This one is my mom&#39;s recipe and is a very simple recipe. Some people use vanilla or even some sort of flan to give it a more structured texture, but I prefer this version. It&#39;s creamy and delicious. I hope you enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot Walnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-22-carrot-walnut-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 13:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-22-carrot-walnut-cake/</guid>
      <description>And now for a very simple but delicious cake. The cake&#39;s recipe is from an aunt of mine and I decided to spruce it up a bit with an orange glaze. &#34;Pantagruel&#34; has several recipes for glazes, and orange+carrot seemed a great combo. It was. On a side note, can you tell that the light in Denmark has already started to change? From now until April I guess I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to start prepping dinner at 2pm if I want to shoot with natural light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagliatelle Bolognese</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I make bolognese sauce, I usually use my own recipe that is probably miles away from the real deal. I call it bolognese because it basically has minced meat and tomato sauce. I&#39;ve looked at recipes of &#34;real&#34; bolognese and they generally include celery and carrot. When I realized that &#34;Pantagruel&#39;s&#34; recipe included those ingredients, I decided to give it a try it. The taste was definitely different from what I had ever tasted and I do hope to do justice to the original Italian recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siam Pumpkin Jam and Almond Tart</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-09-14-siam-pumpkin-jam-and-almond-tart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 14:01:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-09-14-siam-pumpkin-jam-and-almond-tart/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is another Portuguese classic. It&#39;s my mum&#39;s recipe that my sister wrote down a few years ago (and good thing she did because my mother no longer has it). I have been wanting to try it for a long time, but I can&#39;t seem to find siam pumpkin jam in Denmark. So I brought a jar of jam with me from Portugal. This jam has a very distinctive savor and, although I wouldn&#39;t spread it on a slice of bread, when together with almonds and orange it has incredible flavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butter Cookies </title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-09-11-butter-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 15:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-09-11-butter-cookies/</guid>
      <description>So last week I was looking through my cookbooks trying to figure out what to bake the next day, when I came across these cookies. They were super simple to make. Delicate and delicious - the kind of cookies that melt in your mouth. And perfect to go with a cup of tea. This recipe is adapted from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;.Ingredients (10 cookie sandwiches) 60g (half stick) butter at room temperature 2 level tablespoons sugar  1 egg 100g (3/4 cup + 1 tablespoon) flour 2 teaspoons baking powder  raspberry jam q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation - Part II</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-09-09-vacation-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 10:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-09-09-vacation-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the vacation segment, close to Leiria we have plenty of beaches to choose from. For some reason, many of my friends and family spent their childhood summers at Pedrogão. The beach isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly beautiful when compared with other beaches in the region, and the weather and the sea are extremely unpredictable. However, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of sand, good fresh fish and when the weather is nice, you kind of forget how bad it was just the day before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation - Part I</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-09-07-vacation-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 13:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-09-07-vacation-part-i/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been absent for a couple of weeks but for good reason. I went to Portugal on vacation and, as always, it takes me a while to want to post afterwards. But here it is. We grew up in Leiria, but ever since we moved to Denmark, we kind of treat it like we&amp;rsquo;re tourists. A lot of walking around and a lot of photos. Leiria is especially known for its food, so I decided to document some of the stuff that I ate there, as well as the beautiful surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Semifreddo</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-14-chocolate-semifreddo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 23:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-14-chocolate-semifreddo/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll share my favorite dessert as a kid. Perhaps it still is, but now I have to make it. Twenty years ago, my mum came up with the idea and it soon became a classic at my parent&#39;s restaurant (no longer in existence). It is, quite simply, frozen cream enveloped in frozen chocolate mousse, surrounded by melted chocolate. The outside chocolate remains soft, in contrast with the firmer interior, in a perfect blend of texture and sweetness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Fricassee</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-10-chicken-fricassee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 22:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-10-chicken-fricassee/</guid>
      <description>I had never had Chicken Fricassee until now. Not that there&#39;s anything special about the way the chicken is cooked, but the sauce was extraordinary. The butter, the bits of chicken that are left behind and the mushrooms are brought together by the egg yolks resulting in a creamy and tasty sauce. I used a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34;.Ingredients (4 servings) 1 carved chicken or some whole legs and thighs 2 tablespoons butter 1 heaped teaspoon of flour 100g (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine-Braised Beef with Garlic Butter Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 22:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>This recipe resulted in a flavorful braised beef. It&#39;s quite simple to make although it takes nearly 2 hours to cook. The recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;. As for the garlic and parsley butter, it&#39;s a family recipe and it&#39;s incredibly good. In potatoes, on top of a steak, it doesn&#39;t matter. It&#39;s just good.Ingredients (6 servings)For the Braised Beef:
 1kg stewing beef  2 medium onions 2 red peppers  3 tomatoes  2 garlic cloves 1 bay leaf bunch fresh parsley 3dl (1 1/4 cups) white wine 1 tablespoon vinegar 1dl (1/3 cup) olive oil bacon, salt, pepper q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chouriço Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 16:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</guid>
      <description>Chouriço Bread, or Pão com Chouriço as we call it, is a treat you can find in Portuguese markets and fairs. It&#39;s usually baked in a trailer with wood fired ovens. You can also find it year-round in supermarkets, cafes or, more specifically, in Lisbon at Merendeira. There are even places that serve not only chouriço bread, but dried codfish bread, black pudding bread and pork rind bread. Good stuff. The recipe for the bread dough can also be used for baking regular bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Birthday Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 23:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</guid>
      <description>Every since I can remember, all birthdays in my family are celebrated with this cake. There is no real reason not to make it for other occasions, but I can&#39;t help but feel that it is a birthday type of cake. It also helps that my birthday is in July and that I get to use really good strawberries. It&#39;s my favorite cake without a doubt. If you don&#39;t like wet cakes, skip the part where I use the juice of one orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruschetta</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-27-bruschetta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 11:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-27-bruschetta/</guid>
      <description>A simple and flavorful appetizer. It takes 20 minutes total and it&#39;s the perfect starter for a special occasion. And now would be a good time to use good quality extra virgin olive oil, because it will make all the difference. I have been using this recipe for a while, that is the result of several recipes put together.Ingredients (4 servings) 1 loaf of day-old bread 1 medium size tomato 75g fresh mozzarella 1 garlic clove olive oil, vinegar, salt, basil, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg Flan</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-24-egg-flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 23:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-24-egg-flan/</guid>
      <description>Last week I shared a traditional Portuguese main course Onion sauce steaks, but today I will share a classic dessert. You can literally find this in every Portuguese restaurant in Leiria (small town in central Portugal), and one can probably say the same for the remainder of Portugal. It&#39;s simple to make, refreshing and it has incredible flavor. For me the most difficult part is making the caramel due to my irrational fear of getting burned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion Sauce Steaks</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-20-onion-sauce-steaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 10:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-20-onion-sauce-steaks/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is another Portuguese classic. We call it Bifes de Cebolada and you can probably find it in any traditional Portuguese restaurant. I used a recipe from Culinária Portuguesa. This was the first time that I made it in Denmark because until now, I couldn&#39;t seem to find steaks with the right thickness. I didn&#39;t think twice when I actually found them. The sweetness of the onions brings out your gluttonous self and you just can&#39;t stop eating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolaty Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-13-chocolaty-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 23:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-13-chocolaty-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>This was a first and it was mouthwatering. The cake recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34; and the frosting is from Pantagruel. I added the almonds because I simply love the combo chocolate + roasted almonds. The cake was fluffy and the frosting remained shinny until the end. As for the taste, it had just the right amount of chocolate. Not too sweet.Ingredients (12 servings)For the cake
 125g (1 stick) cold butter 125g (1 cup) powdered sugar 125g (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Egg Tarts - Pastel de Nata (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-10-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 22:41:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-10-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Now for part II of the Portuguese Egg Tarts. As I mentioned before, I used store-bought puff pastry when I tried the egg tarts recipe for the first time. I promised a recipe for puff pastry and here it is. But I have to say that I was a little disappointed with the result. I was excepting it to be great but the texture wasn&#39;t 100% right. The flavor however surpassed the store-bought puff pastry without a doubt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John&#39;s Tuna Pasta</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 14:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;m sharing a very easy recipe for pasta. A friend from college came up with it. We used to cook this all the time because it&#39;s cheap and very tasty. And you can also add sweet corn if you like it.Ingredients (2 servings) 1 medium onion 2 garlic cloves 200g (7oz) sliced fresh mushrooms 2 cans of tuna (300g/10oz) 125mL (1/2 cup) of cream parsley for garnish, spaghetti, nutmeg, salt, olive oil, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Egg Tarts - Pastel de Nata (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-03-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 13:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-03-portuguese-egg-tarts-pastel-de-nata-part-i/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been wanting to try a Pastel de Nata recipe for years now. Pantagruel has two recipes, I tried them both and they were kind of bad... The taste was o.k. but the texture was nothing like the real deal. Who knows, maybe in the old days that&#39;s how they did it. Then I remembered that a aunt of mine used to bring a Portuguese egg tart (a whole tart) to my grandparents and thought that it might be worth a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coriander and Cumin Fried Pork</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-29-coriander-and-cumin-fried-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 15:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-29-coriander-and-cumin-fried-pork/</guid>
      <description>I cook this all the time. It&#39;s quick and easy. There are several variations of this recipe in Portugal depending on the region you come from. Where I&#39;m from we call it *Fritada*but, for instance, in the North of Portugal they call it *Rojões*. I served it with rice but a more traditional way would be to top it with chopped pickles and serve it with fries. Unfortunately, I can&#39;t seem to find the right kind of pickles here in Denmark (an assortment of cauliflower, carrots and cucumber).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-06-25-traveling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-06-25-traveling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry for the little hiatus. We went to Portugal and then to Sweden for Dreamhack. Unfortunately, I forgot my camera&amp;rsquo;s SD card in Portugal and as such I only have photos of Portugal from my cellphone. But here we go:
Walked a bit around Leiria during the day.
And at night too.
Hung out with my cat.
Baked an orange sponge cake to take to my grandparents. Shared Mille-feuilles with my sister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey &amp; Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 13:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>And now for another surprisingly good cookies that include olive oil in the recipe (like the Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake). The husband wanted to take some cookies with him to a competition and I usually bake lemon cookies and something else. These were a perfect addition. The recipe is from Pantagruel and it included an alcoholic Portuguese beverage called Aguardentewhich I didn&#39;t include because I don&#39;t like desserts with alcohol. But if you do, just add 9 tablespoons (or 1 cálice if you have any idea what I&#39;m talking about).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-31-strawberry-cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-31-strawberry-cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>I started using this recipe while I was still in college because it was so simple and also because it was a big crowd pleaser. The original recipe included fresh cheese but I have never tried it that way. I&#39;ve made so many changes to the recipe that I consider this my recipe for a no-bake cheesecake. You can use other kinds of jam. I know from experience that with mixed berry jam is just as good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Chicken</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and I&#39;ve used it several times already. It turns out great every time and it&#39;s super simple to prepare. However, this was the first time that I used a free range chicken and the difference was astonishing - the meat was tastier and the sauce left in the pan was better as well. As a side note, although you start by covering the chicken with bacon, you remove it by the end of the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinnamon Rolls</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-24-cinnamon-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 11:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-24-cinnamon-rolls/</guid>
      <description>The first time I visited Denmark, I tried their Cinnamon Rolls from some bakery and I have to say that I wasn&#39;t impressed. I also tried the store bought ones and although I liked them better, I got the feeling that I hadn&#39;t tried the real deal yet. So, when I saw that Aarstiderne had released their recipe on their Facebook page I couldn&#39;t resist giving it a try (Aarstiderne supplies organically produced fruit and vegetables door to door).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Pizza Dough</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 09:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>I really wanted pizza the other day and since Pantagruel had a recipe for a milk pizza dough, it was the perfect opportunity to give it a try. And it was awesome. The crust was crispy and we picked a good mixture of toppings: mozzarella, feta cheese, olives, sweet pepper and onions. As for the sauce, I tried one from Pantagruel as well, but it was too sweet. I ended up using one from Jamie at Home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Salami</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-17-chocolate-salami/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-17-chocolate-salami/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Salami is another classic Portuguese recipe. I wouldn&#39;t say that it is historically old, but while growing up in Portugal you would find it most kids parties. You can also find it supermarkets and coffee shops, but nothing beats the homemade version. It requires no cooking and you can assemble everything in less than half an hour - or even faster if you have a food processor. This recipe is from Pantagruel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Steak with Baked Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 22:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Pan Fried Steak is a Portuguese classic. I cook this at least once every other week and it never fails me. In Portugal, you can find this in almost every restaurant and it&#39;s usually accompanied by french fries, rice and a fried egg. This is my mum&#39;s recipe. As for the baked mashed potatoes, the recipe comes from Pantagruel and they were creamy with an added outside crunch.Ingredients (8-10 tarts)For the Steaks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Roll</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-09-orange-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 20:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-09-orange-roll/</guid>
      <description>An orange roll has very few ingredients and no flour at all. It might sound strange but this specific kind of roll doesn&#39;t need it. There are a lot of different kinds of rolls and it is a rather common dessert in Portugal. It is fresh and light. This is my mum&#39;s recipe which I think is better than the one from Pantagruel (the only difference is in the quantity used).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange &amp; Ginger Chicken Thighs</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 22:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and this was the first time that I gave it a try. The fresh ginger got my attention, but I have to say that it doesn&#39;t sound, or taste, very Portuguese. Nonetheless, it was very tasty and the mixture of orange and ginger resulted in a remarkably fresh aroma, making this recipe perfect for a summer day.Ingredients (3 servings) 6 chicken thighs and/or whole legs 1dl white wine 1 tablespoon vegetable oil 1/2 tablespoon fresh grated ginger zest 1 orange fresh mint leaves salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the Easter topic, here is a recipe for a traditional Easter bread called *&#34;Folar&#34;*, from Pantagruel. The presentation doesn&#39;t exactly match what you would find in Portugal, but the taste sure does. The traditional presentation includes a baked egg in the middle of the bread (that we actually don&#39;t like). And I happened to forgot to brush the bread with egg yolk. :)Ingredients (2 loaves) 475g (4 cups) flour 190g (6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Leg of Lamb</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 14:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</guid>
      <description>There is nothing Eastery about this recipe, except for the fact that in Portugal people tend to have lamb or baby goat for Easter lunch. I don&#39;t think that it is as traditional as it is to have dried codfish for Christmas, for instance. But if you ask someone what they usually eat on Easter Sunday they would probably answer lamb. It&#39;s a simple recipe with and abundance of flavors and, as the majority of roasts, ideal for the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-04-27-im-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 15:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-04-27-im-back/</guid>
      <description>Well that took longer than I expected. But I&amp;rsquo;m back and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll resume the regular posting, starting with a belated Easter recipe. In the meanwhile, here is a photo of my old kitchen and a photo of the new one.
Quite the upgrade, if I may say so myself! :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll be back in two weeks (?)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-03-31-ill-be-back-in-two-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 13:31:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-03-31-ill-be-back-in-two-weeks/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re moving to a new apartment which means that we&amp;rsquo;ll be without internet access for at least two weeks. ಥ_ಥ 
And this week, I tried out a recipe that just wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough so here is a squirrel:
This little guy was hanging around Hans Christian Andersen&amp;rsquo;s grave (hence the Digteren)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thursday: Cock&#39;s &amp; Cows</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-03-29-random-thursday-cocks-cows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 12:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-03-29-random-thursday-cocks-cows/</guid>
      <description>Spring has definitely arrived to Denmark. A friend of ours came to visit which meant a lot of walking and the obligatory visit to Halifax. In Copenhagen, when it starts to get warm, everyone goes outside and sit under the sun for any other purpose than to enjoy the nice weather. And after living here for a while I can understand why.
We went to Halifax the first day and on the second day we decided to show our friend another awesome restaurant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</guid>
      <description>I looked at this recipe several times before deciding that it might be a good one. The fact that it includes olive oil on the ingredients list threw me off at first, but my curiosity got the better of me and I am grateful for it. It was an exceptional good cake with a lot of flavor and a very soft texture. Yes, it asks for a lot of honey, but in the end it was just the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Cheese Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-24-roasted-cheese-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 17:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-24-roasted-cheese-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll share another recipe from Pantagruel. I&#39;m not sure that it&#39;s a Portuguese recipe, but it sounded good and I decided to give it a try. It was very tasty! And it worked out great with the Beef Stew that I shared last week.Ingredients (4 servings) 750g (26oz) finely sliced potatoes 150g (5oz) grated mozzarella 40g (1.5oz) grated parmesan 2 eggs 2 1/2dl (1 cup) milk butter, salt, pepper, nutmeg q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Bean Tarts</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-20-white-bean-tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 15:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-20-white-bean-tarts/</guid>
      <description>White Bean Tarts are a traditional pastry from central Portugal (where I happen to come from). But you can find this tarts all over the country (Lisbon&#39;s airport included). They&#39;re extremely sweet and taste nothing like beans. They work great for a party or to accompany an espresso for your mid-afternoon snack. This was the first time I used this recipe and it worked out great. Ingredients (12 tarts) 500g (2 1/2 cups) caster sugar 300g (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 20:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is a Portuguese classic, just like the Chicken Stew I shared before. It&#39;s from Pantagruel, and it takes about three hours to cook so it&#39;s probably a good weekend recipe. When adding the carrots and shallots, you can also add potatoes, hence avoiding the need to cook a side dish. I didn&#39;t add the potatoes to the pot. Instead, I accompanied the beef stew with roasted potatoes (recipe to come).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 10:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll be sharing a recipe from Pantagruel of a common bread substitute for breakfast or a mid-afternoon snack. I don&#39;t have a mixer, so I just did everything by hand, but if you have a mixer it should be a lot easier. The recipe only asks for a small amount of sugar, but it makes all the difference. They should be soft and fluffy.Ingredients (8-10 buns) 300g (2 1/2 cups) flour 70g (1/3 cup) sugar  25g (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Belly Roast</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-10-pork-belly-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 14:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-10-pork-belly-roast/</guid>
      <description>In kind of an homage to Denmark, I will share a recipe my favorite danish dish. You can find it in the prepared food section in the supermarkets all year long, but it&#39;s also a traditional Christmas dish. I used a Jamie Oliver recipe) which I think is pretty similar to the ones you can find here in Denmark.Ingredients (6 servings) 1,5kg (3.5 pounds) pork belly  2 onions 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 bulb of garlic salt, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camel&#39;s Dribble (Baba de Camelo)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-06-camels-dribble-baba-de-camelo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 12:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-06-camels-dribble-baba-de-camelo/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll share my mum&#39;s recipe for Camel&#39;s Dribble. Don&#39;t let the title scare you. Camel&#39;s Dribble is basically caramel mousse. It&#39;s extremely sweet and has a very intense flavor. Sweeter than Chocolate Mousse for instance. Consider yourself warned - if you like sweets, there&#39;s something delicious on your way.Ingredients (10 servings) 1 can of cooked or uncooked sweet condensed milk 5 eggs  Instructions (Time: 3-6 hours)If you can find cooked sweet condensed milk in your supermarket then you can skip this step, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll need to boil your uncooked can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stew</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 15:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</guid>
      <description>And now another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe, although I feel like I&#39;ve eaten this dish numerous times before. It reminds me of the chicken stew that used to be served at my university&#39;s dining hall. A better version of it for sure. When defining &#34;comfort food&#34; this dish should definitely be included. However, it takes a long time to cook so you should try it during the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thursday: Denmark 2</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-03-02-random-thursday-denmark-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 17:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-03-02-random-thursday-denmark-2/</guid>
      <description>More like Friday I know. I have mentioned before that I have a Diana F+ (120mm) and that the husband has an Holga (35mm). This means that occasionally we need to develop film. Yesterday was one of those days, hence the delay in this post.
When we moved here, we came across a great store called Photografica. If you ever need to develop film or buy a camera (new or used), in Copenhagen, this is the place to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Sponge Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 09:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned on a post about the chocolate mousse that I know three dessert recipes by heart. I&#39;ve shared the pancake recipe, the chocolate mousse and now it&#39;s time for the Sponge Cake. This time I decided to make an Orange Sponge Cake, but you can use the zest of a lemon instead of a zest of an orange. In my family, we make this cake regularly for guests or to take with us to my grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Punched Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-25-portuguese-punched-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 09:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-25-portuguese-punched-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>It was time to share with you the recipe that gave name to this blog. We don&#39;t eat this as often as we should for something so tasty, because we don&#39;t have &#34;easy&#34; access to salted cod fish here in Denmark. It&#39;s sad but true. And this potatoes just ask for it. I actually get that feeling that there&#39;s something missing. But it&amp;rsquo;s better to eat them this way than to not eat them at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portuguese Delicacies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-02-23-portuguese-delicacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 12:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-02-23-portuguese-delicacies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a word for what happened at our place last week but I don&amp;rsquo;t think that there&amp;rsquo;s an equivalent in english to petisco. A petisco is when you create a spread of food that can be cooked or not and that is usually eaten outside of traditional meal times. We started at 4pm. You slowly pick bits of this and that, along with your drink of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Bonbons (Brigadeiros)</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-21-chocolate-bonbons-brigadeiros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 09:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-21-chocolate-bonbons-brigadeiros/</guid>
      <description>These chocolate bonbons aren&#39;t really portuguese. More like brazilian. But they are quite common in Portugal and are amazing. They have a very intense flavor and gooey texture. This was the first time that I made this in Denmark because, until now, I wasn&#39;t able to find sweet condensed milk in the supermarket. But the other day there it was on the baking supplies&#39; aisle. :) It&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant Gratin</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-14-eggplant-gratin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 12:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-14-eggplant-gratin/</guid>
      <description>The first time I tried eggplant gratin was at my mother-in-law&#39;s house. And yesterday I decided to give it a try on my own. I&#39;m not sure that the recipe that I came up with is an accurate replica but it tasted surprisingly good! The husband even said &#34;This actually tastes good, right?&#34; with a very confused look on his face. High praise. Every time I try to reproduce one of his mothers recipe I always get this gem &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Valentine&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-02-14-happy-valentines-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 10:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-02-14-happy-valentines-day/</guid>
      <description>As seen on Petite Kitchenesse. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantagruel&#39;s Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>And here is another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe and it did not disappoint. I will definitely make this chocolate cake again, but I will change the baking time for the next time I use this one. The recipe asked for 45-50 minutes in the oven and after 30 minutes I checked it with a toothpick and it was done! Ingredients (12 servings) 225g flour (1 cup) (+ a bit for the cake pan) 150g granulated sugar (3/4 cup) 130g butter at room temperature (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thursday: Denmark</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-02-09-random-thursday-denmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 12:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-02-09-random-thursday-denmark/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my first Random Thursday. This space will be dedicated to any kind of topic that I feel like writing about/show the world that doesn&amp;rsquo;t include a recipe. I think that it might be a good idea to explain why there is a photo of a burger in the slide show! The burger in the photo is in my opinion the best burger in Copenhagen. It also happens to be available in the best burger place in the city: Halifax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Mousse</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-09-chocolate-mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 10:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-09-chocolate-mousse/</guid>
      <description>While growing up Chocolate Mousse was a staple at my parents house in every special occasion. Christmas, Easter, birthdays, you name it and Chocolate Mousse was there. It&#39;s one of the three recipes that I know by heart: chocolate mousse, pancakes and sponge cake. It requires patience with the egg whites, but other than that there is really not much to it.Ingredients (6-8 servings) 6 eggs 6 tablespoons of granulated sugar 200g of good dark chocolate (7oz) 1 tablespoon of butter  Instructions (Time: 4 hours)Start by melting the chocolate with the butter in a double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Desserts are my favorite things to cook. This recipe has turned out a great success every time I used it. It takes some time to finish but in the end is totally worth it. The husband loves these cookies. They keep well and make a great combo with coffee or tea. And it&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!Ingredients (30 cookies) 1/2kg white flour (4 cups) 200g granulated sugar (7oz) 250g butter at room temperature (9oz) 2 eggs 1 small lemon  Instructions (Time: 2 hours)Start by beating the eggs with the sugar and the zest of the lemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mustard Pork Tenderloin</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-31-mustard-pork-tenderloin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 12:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-31-mustard-pork-tenderloin/</guid>
      <description>And now a recipe from Pantagruel. It&#39;s called &#34;Lombo de porco assado com mostarda&#34;. As per usual, there&amp;rsquo;s no mention of the oven temperature or cooking time. But it worked out great! The mustard complements the pork quite well. And here is a picture from Pantagruel of the pork cuts for the cook that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know them yet.
Ingredients (2-3 servings) 1 pork tenderloin (500g or 1lb) 3 tablespoons Dijon mustard 1 tablespoon vinegar salt, white wine q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday&#39;s Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-28-saturdays-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 12:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-28-saturdays-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>The best away to celebrate our day off is to start the day with our favorite breakfast: Pancakes! We&#39;ve been eating pancakes on Saturdays ever since we moved to Denmark. It&#39;s easy to make and we never get tired of it. With some butter and maple syrup, a cup of coffee and orange juice... Saturdays are the best! Ingredients (2-3 servings) 1 egg 250mL milk (or 1 cup) 120g flour (1 cup) 1 tablespoon granulated sugar 1/3 teaspoon salt 2 heaped teaspoons baking powder  2 tablespoons vegetable oil or melted butter  butter and maple syrup to taste  (Note: You can just use the same measuring instrument you used for the milk to measure the flour, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a measuring cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpeas Salad</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-24-chickpeas-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 15:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-24-chickpeas-salad/</guid>
      <description>When you don&#39;t have time or patience to come up with something to cook this recipe is probably the answer to your problems. Super easy to make and it only takes the time that the eggs need do cook. And I don&#39;t know about you, but I always have these ingredients in my pantry. Win win win. Ingredients (3 servings) 2 cans of chickpeas 1 can of tuna in oil (140g or 5oz) 1 small red onion 2 eggs parsley, olive oil, vinegar, salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkey Steaks with Cream Sauce and Cabbage Rice</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-21-turkey-steaks-with-cream-sauce-and-cabbage-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 18:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-21-turkey-steaks-with-cream-sauce-and-cabbage-rice/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple meal but very tasty. I sometimes make the turkey steaks during the week with broccoli or some other vegetable, but because today is Saturday let&#39;s load up on carbs! No source for the recipe. It&#39;s just one of those things that I have eaten all my life. My mum actually makes this rice for special occasions because it&#39;s incredibly tasty.Ingredients (2 servings)Turkey Steaks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-01-19-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 09:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/life/2012-01-19-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
It&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and I&amp;rsquo;m about to leave for the gym. Still don&amp;rsquo;t know what to cook Saturday. One of the things that bugs me the most about living in Denmark is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find Portuguese ingredients that are crucial for some recipes. And that it&amp;rsquo;s way my recipes won&amp;rsquo;t be all of Portuguese origin. We do go to Portugal every 3 months, give or take, which means that we can bring with us some &amp;ldquo;chouriço&amp;rdquo; or even some &amp;ldquo;bacalhau&amp;rdquo; (cod fish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/about/</guid>
      <description>about things</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantagruel</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/pantagruel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/pantagruel/</guid>
      <description>I have a few cooking books, but since I want to explore Portuguese cooking I will look for recipes in the only Portuguese book that I own (for now):
&amp;ldquo;O livro de Pantagruel&amp;rdquo; has 5000 recipes. The first edition came out in 1946 with only 1500 recipes. It is now on the 74th edition retaining the same structure and the same quality recipes. No photos or extensive explanations. The cake recipes don&amp;rsquo;t even have a baking temperature, only an interval from which you can choose the temperature that works best for you oven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/searchresults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/searchresults/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
