<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>butter on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/butter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in butter on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 15:55:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/butter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Butter Cookies </title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-09-11-butter-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 15:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-09-11-butter-cookies/</guid>
      <description>So last week I was looking through my cookbooks trying to figure out what to bake the next day, when I came across these cookies. They were super simple to make. Delicate and delicious - the kind of cookies that melt in your mouth. And perfect to go with a cup of tea. This recipe is adapted from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;.Ingredients (10 cookie sandwiches) 60g (half stick) butter at room temperature 2 level tablespoons sugar  1 egg 100g (3/4 cup + 1 tablespoon) flour 2 teaspoons baking powder  raspberry jam q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine-Braised Beef with Garlic Butter Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 22:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>This recipe resulted in a flavorful braised beef. It&#39;s quite simple to make although it takes nearly 2 hours to cook. The recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;. As for the garlic and parsley butter, it&#39;s a family recipe and it&#39;s incredibly good. In potatoes, on top of a steak, it doesn&#39;t matter. It&#39;s just good.Ingredients (6 servings)For the Braised Beef:
 1kg stewing beef  2 medium onions 2 red peppers  3 tomatoes  2 garlic cloves 1 bay leaf bunch fresh parsley 3dl (1 1/4 cups) white wine 1 tablespoon vinegar 1dl (1/3 cup) olive oil bacon, salt, pepper q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-31-strawberry-cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-31-strawberry-cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>I started using this recipe while I was still in college because it was so simple and also because it was a big crowd pleaser. The original recipe included fresh cheese but I have never tried it that way. I&#39;ve made so many changes to the recipe that I consider this my recipe for a no-bake cheesecake. You can use other kinds of jam. I know from experience that with mixed berry jam is just as good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Chicken</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and I&#39;ve used it several times already. It turns out great every time and it&#39;s super simple to prepare. However, this was the first time that I used a free range chicken and the difference was astonishing - the meat was tastier and the sauce left in the pan was better as well. As a side note, although you start by covering the chicken with bacon, you remove it by the end of the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
