<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chicken on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/chicken/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chicken on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 22:47:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Fricassee</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-10-chicken-fricassee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 22:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-10-chicken-fricassee/</guid>
      <description>I had never had Chicken Fricassee until now. Not that there&#39;s anything special about the way the chicken is cooked, but the sauce was extraordinary. The butter, the bits of chicken that are left behind and the mushrooms are brought together by the egg yolks resulting in a creamy and tasty sauce. I used a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34;.Ingredients (4 servings) 1 carved chicken or some whole legs and thighs 2 tablespoons butter 1 heaped teaspoon of flour 100g (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Chicken</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and I&#39;ve used it several times already. It turns out great every time and it&#39;s super simple to prepare. However, this was the first time that I used a free range chicken and the difference was astonishing - the meat was tastier and the sauce left in the pan was better as well. As a side note, although you start by covering the chicken with bacon, you remove it by the end of the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange &amp; Ginger Chicken Thighs</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 22:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and this was the first time that I gave it a try. The fresh ginger got my attention, but I have to say that it doesn&#39;t sound, or taste, very Portuguese. Nonetheless, it was very tasty and the mixture of orange and ginger resulted in a remarkably fresh aroma, making this recipe perfect for a summer day.Ingredients (3 servings) 6 chicken thighs and/or whole legs 1dl white wine 1 tablespoon vegetable oil 1/2 tablespoon fresh grated ginger zest 1 orange fresh mint leaves salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stew</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 15:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</guid>
      <description>And now another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe, although I feel like I&#39;ve eaten this dish numerous times before. It reminds me of the chicken stew that used to be served at my university&#39;s dining hall. A better version of it for sure. When defining &#34;comfort food&#34; this dish should definitely be included. However, it takes a long time to cook so you should try it during the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
