<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cookies on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/cookies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cookies on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 16:55:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/cookies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Valentine&#39;s Day Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2013-02-07-valentines-day-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 16:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2013-02-07-valentines-day-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Valentine&#39;s Day is almost here and I just had to make something in the shape of an heart. Last year was breakfast, but this year I made cinnamon cookies. Last Christmas I got a classic Portuguese cookbook called &amp;ldquo;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&amp;rdquo; by Maria de Lourdes Modesto. It has amazing detailed recipes from all over the country and it even has some pictures (as opposed to Pantagruel). This is the third recipe that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried from this book and it turned out even better than I was expecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butter Cookies </title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-09-11-butter-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 15:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-09-11-butter-cookies/</guid>
      <description>So last week I was looking through my cookbooks trying to figure out what to bake the next day, when I came across these cookies. They were super simple to make. Delicate and delicious - the kind of cookies that melt in your mouth. And perfect to go with a cup of tea. This recipe is adapted from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;.Ingredients (10 cookie sandwiches) 60g (half stick) butter at room temperature 2 level tablespoons sugar  1 egg 100g (3/4 cup + 1 tablespoon) flour 2 teaspoons baking powder  raspberry jam q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey &amp; Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 13:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>And now for another surprisingly good cookies that include olive oil in the recipe (like the Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake). The husband wanted to take some cookies with him to a competition and I usually bake lemon cookies and something else. These were a perfect addition. The recipe is from Pantagruel and it included an alcoholic Portuguese beverage called Aguardentewhich I didn&#39;t include because I don&#39;t like desserts with alcohol. But if you do, just add 9 tablespoons (or 1 cálice if you have any idea what I&#39;m talking about).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Desserts are my favorite things to cook. This recipe has turned out a great success every time I used it. It takes some time to finish but in the end is totally worth it. The husband loves these cookies. They keep well and make a great combo with coffee or tea. And it&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!Ingredients (30 cookies) 1/2kg white flour (4 cups) 200g granulated sugar (7oz) 250g butter at room temperature (9oz) 2 eggs 1 small lemon  Instructions (Time: 2 hours)Start by beating the eggs with the sugar and the zest of the lemon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
