<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>roast on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/roast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in roast on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:02:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/roast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Pork Carré</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2013-03-17-roasted-pork-carre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2013-03-17-roasted-pork-carre/</guid>
      <description>I grew up eating pork carré occasionally and was truly surprised when I found this meat cut here in Denmark, even though carré doesn&#39;t sound Portuguese at all. And with a recognizable name! (Svine carré). I made some changes to a recipe from Culinária Portuguese and it worked perfectly. It is a moist pork roast and I think the fat on top helps to give it flavor. This recipe followed a series of mishaps in the last month, so I was more than happy with how wonderful this roast turned out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Chicken</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and I&#39;ve used it several times already. It turns out great every time and it&#39;s super simple to prepare. However, this was the first time that I used a free range chicken and the difference was astonishing - the meat was tastier and the sauce left in the pan was better as well. As a side note, although you start by covering the chicken with bacon, you remove it by the end of the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Belly Roast</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-10-pork-belly-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 14:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-10-pork-belly-roast/</guid>
      <description>In kind of an homage to Denmark, I will share a recipe my favorite danish dish. You can find it in the prepared food section in the supermarkets all year long, but it&#39;s also a traditional Christmas dish. I used a Jamie Oliver recipe) which I think is pretty similar to the ones you can find here in Denmark.Ingredients (6 servings) 1,5kg (3.5 pounds) pork belly  2 onions 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 bulb of garlic salt, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
