<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mousse on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/mousse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mousse on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 12:26:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/mousse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Camel&#39;s Dribble (Baba de Camelo)</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-06-camels-dribble-baba-de-camelo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 12:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-06-camels-dribble-baba-de-camelo/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll share my mum&#39;s recipe for Camel&#39;s Dribble. Don&#39;t let the title scare you. Camel&#39;s Dribble is basically caramel mousse. It&#39;s extremely sweet and has a very intense flavor. Sweeter than Chocolate Mousse for instance. Consider yourself warned - if you like sweets, there&#39;s something delicious on your way.Ingredients (10 servings) 1 can of cooked or uncooked sweet condensed milk 5 eggs  Instructions (Time: 3-6 hours)If you can find cooked sweet condensed milk in your supermarket then you can skip this step, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll need to boil your uncooked can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Mousse</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-09-chocolate-mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 10:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-09-chocolate-mousse/</guid>
      <description>While growing up Chocolate Mousse was a staple at my parents house in every special occasion. Christmas, Easter, birthdays, you name it and Chocolate Mousse was there. It&#39;s one of the three recipes that I know by heart: chocolate mousse, pancakes and sponge cake. It requires patience with the egg whites, but other than that there is really not much to it.Ingredients (6-8 servings) 6 eggs 6 tablespoons of granulated sugar 200g of good dark chocolate (7oz) 1 tablespoon of butter  Instructions (Time: 4 hours)Start by melting the chocolate with the butter in a double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
