<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chocolate on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/chocolate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chocolate on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 23:12:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/chocolate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Semifreddo</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-08-14-chocolate-semifreddo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 23:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-08-14-chocolate-semifreddo/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll share my favorite dessert as a kid. Perhaps it still is, but now I have to make it. Twenty years ago, my mum came up with the idea and it soon became a classic at my parent&#39;s restaurant (no longer in existence). It is, quite simply, frozen cream enveloped in frozen chocolate mousse, surrounded by melted chocolate. The outside chocolate remains soft, in contrast with the firmer interior, in a perfect blend of texture and sweetness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolaty Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-13-chocolaty-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 23:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-13-chocolaty-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>This was a first and it was mouthwatering. The cake recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34; and the frosting is from Pantagruel. I added the almonds because I simply love the combo chocolate + roasted almonds. The cake was fluffy and the frosting remained shinny until the end. As for the taste, it had just the right amount of chocolate. Not too sweet.Ingredients (12 servings)For the cake
 125g (1 stick) cold butter 125g (1 cup) powdered sugar 125g (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Salami</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-17-chocolate-salami/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-17-chocolate-salami/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Salami is another classic Portuguese recipe. I wouldn&#39;t say that it is historically old, but while growing up in Portugal you would find it most kids parties. You can also find it supermarkets and coffee shops, but nothing beats the homemade version. It requires no cooking and you can assemble everything in less than half an hour - or even faster if you have a food processor. This recipe is from Pantagruel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Bonbons (Brigadeiros)</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-21-chocolate-bonbons-brigadeiros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 09:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-21-chocolate-bonbons-brigadeiros/</guid>
      <description>These chocolate bonbons aren&#39;t really portuguese. More like brazilian. But they are quite common in Portugal and are amazing. They have a very intense flavor and gooey texture. This was the first time that I made this in Denmark because, until now, I wasn&#39;t able to find sweet condensed milk in the supermarket. But the other day there it was on the baking supplies&#39; aisle. :) It&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantagruel&#39;s Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>And here is another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe and it did not disappoint. I will definitely make this chocolate cake again, but I will change the baking time for the next time I use this one. The recipe asked for 45-50 minutes in the oven and after 30 minutes I checked it with a toothpick and it was done! Ingredients (12 servings) 225g flour (1 cup) (+ a bit for the cake pan) 150g granulated sugar (3/4 cup) 130g butter at room temperature (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Mousse</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-09-chocolate-mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 10:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-09-chocolate-mousse/</guid>
      <description>While growing up Chocolate Mousse was a staple at my parents house in every special occasion. Christmas, Easter, birthdays, you name it and Chocolate Mousse was there. It&#39;s one of the three recipes that I know by heart: chocolate mousse, pancakes and sponge cake. It requires patience with the egg whites, but other than that there is really not much to it.Ingredients (6-8 servings) 6 eggs 6 tablespoons of granulated sugar 200g of good dark chocolate (7oz) 1 tablespoon of butter  Instructions (Time: 4 hours)Start by melting the chocolate with the butter in a double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
