<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>special occasion on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/special-occasion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in special occasion on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:46:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/special-occasion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread II</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</guid>
      <description>I hope you&#39;re having a nice Easter. Last year I shared a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34; for a traditional Portuguese Easter bread, but I completely failed its presentation. So this year I decided to try a new recipe and this time from &#34;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&#34;. And I&#39;m glad I decided to give it a try because I actually prefer this version. The egg in the middle is completely optional. I&amp;rsquo;ve never in my life ate the boiled egg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broas do Bolinho</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 14:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</guid>
      <description>Now this is a first. I couldn&#39;t find an appropriate title in English for this post so there you go, good old Portuguese. We don&#39;t really celebrate Halloween in Portugal. Instead, on the 1st of November, children wake up early in the morning and go door-to-door asking for Bolinho or Pão-por-Deus - basically they get treats that can be in the form of these rolls I&#39;m sharing today, chocolates, money or even walnuts/chestnuts if you&#39;re terribly unlucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Birthday Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 23:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</guid>
      <description>Every since I can remember, all birthdays in my family are celebrated with this cake. There is no real reason not to make it for other occasions, but I can&#39;t help but feel that it is a birthday type of cake. It also helps that my birthday is in July and that I get to use really good strawberries. It&#39;s my favorite cake without a doubt. If you don&#39;t like wet cakes, skip the part where I use the juice of one orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the Easter topic, here is a recipe for a traditional Easter bread called *&#34;Folar&#34;*, from Pantagruel. The presentation doesn&#39;t exactly match what you would find in Portugal, but the taste sure does. The traditional presentation includes a baked egg in the middle of the bread (that we actually don&#39;t like). And I happened to forgot to brush the bread with egg yolk. :)Ingredients (2 loaves) 475g (4 cups) flour 190g (6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Leg of Lamb</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 14:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</guid>
      <description>There is nothing Eastery about this recipe, except for the fact that in Portugal people tend to have lamb or baby goat for Easter lunch. I don&#39;t think that it is as traditional as it is to have dried codfish for Christmas, for instance. But if you ask someone what they usually eat on Easter Sunday they would probably answer lamb. It&#39;s a simple recipe with and abundance of flavors and, as the majority of roasts, ideal for the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
