<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>italian on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/italian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in italian on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 18:36:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tagliatelle Bolognese</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I make bolognese sauce, I usually use my own recipe that is probably miles away from the real deal. I call it bolognese because it basically has minced meat and tomato sauce. I&#39;ve looked at recipes of &#34;real&#34; bolognese and they generally include celery and carrot. When I realized that &#34;Pantagruel&#39;s&#34; recipe included those ingredients, I decided to give it a try it. The taste was definitely different from what I had ever tasted and I do hope to do justice to the original Italian recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruschetta</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-27-bruschetta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 11:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-27-bruschetta/</guid>
      <description>A simple and flavorful appetizer. It takes 20 minutes total and it&#39;s the perfect starter for a special occasion. And now would be a good time to use good quality extra virgin olive oil, because it will make all the difference. I have been using this recipe for a while, that is the result of several recipes put together.Ingredients (4 servings) 1 loaf of day-old bread 1 medium size tomato 75g fresh mozzarella 1 garlic clove olive oil, vinegar, salt, basil, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John&#39;s Tuna Pasta</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 14:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;m sharing a very easy recipe for pasta. A friend from college came up with it. We used to cook this all the time because it&#39;s cheap and very tasty. And you can also add sweet corn if you like it.Ingredients (2 servings) 1 medium onion 2 garlic cloves 200g (7oz) sliced fresh mushrooms 2 cans of tuna (300g/10oz) 125mL (1/2 cup) of cream parsley for garnish, spaghetti, nutmeg, salt, olive oil, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Pizza Dough</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 09:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>I really wanted pizza the other day and since Pantagruel had a recipe for a milk pizza dough, it was the perfect opportunity to give it a try. And it was awesome. The crust was crispy and we picked a good mixture of toppings: mozzarella, feta cheese, olives, sweet pepper and onions. As for the sauce, I tried one from Pantagruel as well, but it was too sweet. I ended up using one from Jamie at Home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
