<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pantagruel on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/pantagruel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pantagruel on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 16:26:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/pantagruel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Flan</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-11-21-apple-flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 16:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-11-21-apple-flan/</guid>
      <description>I talked raisins and nuts last week and it wouldn&#39;t be right to skip cooking something with apples this autumn. Whenever I&#39;m out of ideas for new recipes I just pick &#34;Pantagruel&#34; and look for inspiration. This recipe seemed simple enough and, more importantly, the main focus was on apples. The recipe called for Reinetteapples. These apples originated in France and are oftentimes used as a cooking apples in Portugal. Unfortunately, I couldn&#39;t find them in Denmark and so I used Royal Gala instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey &amp; Cinnamon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 13:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-06-05-honey-cinnamon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>And now for another surprisingly good cookies that include olive oil in the recipe (like the Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake). The husband wanted to take some cookies with him to a competition and I usually bake lemon cookies and something else. These were a perfect addition. The recipe is from Pantagruel and it included an alcoholic Portuguese beverage called Aguardentewhich I didn&#39;t include because I don&#39;t like desserts with alcohol. But if you do, just add 9 tablespoons (or 1 cálice if you have any idea what I&#39;m talking about).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Chicken</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and I&#39;ve used it several times already. It turns out great every time and it&#39;s super simple to prepare. However, this was the first time that I used a free range chicken and the difference was astonishing - the meat was tastier and the sauce left in the pan was better as well. As a side note, although you start by covering the chicken with bacon, you remove it by the end of the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Pizza Dough</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 09:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>I really wanted pizza the other day and since Pantagruel had a recipe for a milk pizza dough, it was the perfect opportunity to give it a try. And it was awesome. The crust was crispy and we picked a good mixture of toppings: mozzarella, feta cheese, olives, sweet pepper and onions. As for the sauce, I tried one from Pantagruel as well, but it was too sweet. I ended up using one from Jamie at Home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Salami</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-17-chocolate-salami/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-17-chocolate-salami/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Salami is another classic Portuguese recipe. I wouldn&#39;t say that it is historically old, but while growing up in Portugal you would find it most kids parties. You can also find it supermarkets and coffee shops, but nothing beats the homemade version. It requires no cooking and you can assemble everything in less than half an hour - or even faster if you have a food processor. This recipe is from Pantagruel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Steak with Baked Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 22:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Pan Fried Steak is a Portuguese classic. I cook this at least once every other week and it never fails me. In Portugal, you can find this in almost every restaurant and it&#39;s usually accompanied by french fries, rice and a fried egg. This is my mum&#39;s recipe. As for the baked mashed potatoes, the recipe comes from Pantagruel and they were creamy with an added outside crunch.Ingredients (8-10 tarts)For the Steaks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange &amp; Ginger Chicken Thighs</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 22:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and this was the first time that I gave it a try. The fresh ginger got my attention, but I have to say that it doesn&#39;t sound, or taste, very Portuguese. Nonetheless, it was very tasty and the mixture of orange and ginger resulted in a remarkably fresh aroma, making this recipe perfect for a summer day.Ingredients (3 servings) 6 chicken thighs and/or whole legs 1dl white wine 1 tablespoon vegetable oil 1/2 tablespoon fresh grated ginger zest 1 orange fresh mint leaves salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the Easter topic, here is a recipe for a traditional Easter bread called *&#34;Folar&#34;*, from Pantagruel. The presentation doesn&#39;t exactly match what you would find in Portugal, but the taste sure does. The traditional presentation includes a baked egg in the middle of the bread (that we actually don&#39;t like). And I happened to forgot to brush the bread with egg yolk. :)Ingredients (2 loaves) 475g (4 cups) flour 190g (6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Leg of Lamb</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 14:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</guid>
      <description>There is nothing Eastery about this recipe, except for the fact that in Portugal people tend to have lamb or baby goat for Easter lunch. I don&#39;t think that it is as traditional as it is to have dried codfish for Christmas, for instance. But if you ask someone what they usually eat on Easter Sunday they would probably answer lamb. It&#39;s a simple recipe with and abundance of flavors and, as the majority of roasts, ideal for the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</guid>
      <description>I looked at this recipe several times before deciding that it might be a good one. The fact that it includes olive oil on the ingredients list threw me off at first, but my curiosity got the better of me and I am grateful for it. It was an exceptional good cake with a lot of flavor and a very soft texture. Yes, it asks for a lot of honey, but in the end it was just the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Cheese Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-24-roasted-cheese-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 17:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-24-roasted-cheese-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll share another recipe from Pantagruel. I&#39;m not sure that it&#39;s a Portuguese recipe, but it sounded good and I decided to give it a try. It was very tasty! And it worked out great with the Beef Stew that I shared last week.Ingredients (4 servings) 750g (26oz) finely sliced potatoes 150g (5oz) grated mozzarella 40g (1.5oz) grated parmesan 2 eggs 2 1/2dl (1 cup) milk butter, salt, pepper, nutmeg q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Bean Tarts</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-20-white-bean-tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 15:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-20-white-bean-tarts/</guid>
      <description>White Bean Tarts are a traditional pastry from central Portugal (where I happen to come from). But you can find this tarts all over the country (Lisbon&#39;s airport included). They&#39;re extremely sweet and taste nothing like beans. They work great for a party or to accompany an espresso for your mid-afternoon snack. This was the first time I used this recipe and it worked out great. Ingredients (12 tarts) 500g (2 1/2 cups) caster sugar 300g (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 20:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is a Portuguese classic, just like the Chicken Stew I shared before. It&#39;s from Pantagruel, and it takes about three hours to cook so it&#39;s probably a good weekend recipe. When adding the carrots and shallots, you can also add potatoes, hence avoiding the need to cook a side dish. I didn&#39;t add the potatoes to the pot. Instead, I accompanied the beef stew with roasted potatoes (recipe to come).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Bread</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 10:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll be sharing a recipe from Pantagruel of a common bread substitute for breakfast or a mid-afternoon snack. I don&#39;t have a mixer, so I just did everything by hand, but if you have a mixer it should be a lot easier. The recipe only asks for a small amount of sugar, but it makes all the difference. They should be soft and fluffy.Ingredients (8-10 buns) 300g (2 1/2 cups) flour 70g (1/3 cup) sugar  25g (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stew</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 15:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</guid>
      <description>And now another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe, although I feel like I&#39;ve eaten this dish numerous times before. It reminds me of the chicken stew that used to be served at my university&#39;s dining hall. A better version of it for sure. When defining &#34;comfort food&#34; this dish should definitely be included. However, it takes a long time to cook so you should try it during the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Bonbons (Brigadeiros)</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-21-chocolate-bonbons-brigadeiros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 09:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-21-chocolate-bonbons-brigadeiros/</guid>
      <description>These chocolate bonbons aren&#39;t really portuguese. More like brazilian. But they are quite common in Portugal and are amazing. They have a very intense flavor and gooey texture. This was the first time that I made this in Denmark because, until now, I wasn&#39;t able to find sweet condensed milk in the supermarket. But the other day there it was on the baking supplies&#39; aisle. :) It&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantagruel&#39;s Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>And here is another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe and it did not disappoint. I will definitely make this chocolate cake again, but I will change the baking time for the next time I use this one. The recipe asked for 45-50 minutes in the oven and after 30 minutes I checked it with a toothpick and it was done! Ingredients (12 servings) 225g flour (1 cup) (+ a bit for the cake pan) 150g granulated sugar (3/4 cup) 130g butter at room temperature (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Cookies</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-04-lemon-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Desserts are my favorite things to cook. This recipe has turned out a great success every time I used it. It takes some time to finish but in the end is totally worth it. The husband loves these cookies. They keep well and make a great combo with coffee or tea. And it&#39;s another recipe from Pantagruel!Ingredients (30 cookies) 1/2kg white flour (4 cups) 200g granulated sugar (7oz) 250g butter at room temperature (9oz) 2 eggs 1 small lemon  Instructions (Time: 2 hours)Start by beating the eggs with the sugar and the zest of the lemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mustard Pork Tenderloin</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-01-31-mustard-pork-tenderloin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 12:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-01-31-mustard-pork-tenderloin/</guid>
      <description>And now a recipe from Pantagruel. It&#39;s called &#34;Lombo de porco assado com mostarda&#34;. As per usual, there&amp;rsquo;s no mention of the oven temperature or cooking time. But it worked out great! The mustard complements the pork quite well. And here is a picture from Pantagruel of the pork cuts for the cook that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know them yet.
Ingredients (2-3 servings) 1 pork tenderloin (500g or 1lb) 3 tablespoons Dijon mustard 1 tablespoon vinegar salt, white wine q.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
