<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cake on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/cake/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cake on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 13:55:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/cake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carrot Walnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-22-carrot-walnut-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 13:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-22-carrot-walnut-cake/</guid>
      <description>And now for a very simple but delicious cake. The cake&#39;s recipe is from an aunt of mine and I decided to spruce it up a bit with an orange glaze. &#34;Pantagruel&#34; has several recipes for glazes, and orange+carrot seemed a great combo. It was. On a side note, can you tell that the light in Denmark has already started to change? From now until April I guess I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to start prepping dinner at 2pm if I want to shoot with natural light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Birthday Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 23:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-31-strawberry-birthday-cake/</guid>
      <description>Every since I can remember, all birthdays in my family are celebrated with this cake. There is no real reason not to make it for other occasions, but I can&#39;t help but feel that it is a birthday type of cake. It also helps that my birthday is in July and that I get to use really good strawberries. It&#39;s my favorite cake without a doubt. If you don&#39;t like wet cakes, skip the part where I use the juice of one orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolaty Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-13-chocolaty-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 23:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-13-chocolaty-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>This was a first and it was mouthwatering. The cake recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34; and the frosting is from Pantagruel. I added the almonds because I simply love the combo chocolate + roasted almonds. The cake was fluffy and the frosting remained shinny until the end. As for the taste, it had just the right amount of chocolate. Not too sweet.Ingredients (12 servings)For the cake
 125g (1 stick) cold butter 125g (1 cup) powdered sugar 125g (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algarve&#39;s Honey Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-27-algarves-honey-cake/</guid>
      <description>I looked at this recipe several times before deciding that it might be a good one. The fact that it includes olive oil on the ingredients list threw me off at first, but my curiosity got the better of me and I am grateful for it. It was an exceptional good cake with a lot of flavor and a very soft texture. Yes, it asks for a lot of honey, but in the end it was just the right amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Sponge Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 09:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-28-orange-sponge-cake/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned on a post about the chocolate mousse that I know three dessert recipes by heart. I&#39;ve shared the pancake recipe, the chocolate mousse and now it&#39;s time for the Sponge Cake. This time I decided to make an Orange Sponge Cake, but you can use the zest of a lemon instead of a zest of an orange. In my family, we make this cake regularly for guests or to take with us to my grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantagruel&#39;s Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-12-pantagruels-chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>And here is another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe and it did not disappoint. I will definitely make this chocolate cake again, but I will change the baking time for the next time I use this one. The recipe asked for 45-50 minutes in the oven and after 30 minutes I checked it with a toothpick and it was done! Ingredients (12 servings) 225g flour (1 cup) (+ a bit for the cake pan) 150g granulated sugar (3/4 cup) 130g butter at room temperature (4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
