<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>main course on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/courses/main-course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in main course on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:02:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/courses/main-course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Pork Carré</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-17-roasted-pork-carre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-17-roasted-pork-carre/</guid>
      <description>I grew up eating pork carré occasionally and was truly surprised when I found this meat cut here in Denmark, even though carré doesn&#39;t sound Portuguese at all. And with a recognizable name! (Svine carré). I made some changes to a recipe from Culinária Portuguese and it worked perfectly. It is a moist pork roast and I think the fat on top helps to give it flavor. This recipe followed a series of mishaps in the last month, so I was more than happy with how wonderful this roast turned out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacalhau with Broa</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-08-bacalhau-with-broa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 22:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-12-08-bacalhau-with-broa/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of this Christmas season, here is a recipe worthy of a Christmas dinner in Portugal. Bacalhau, or codfish that has been salted and dried, is commonly eaten on Christmas Eve in Portugal, roasted or boiled accompanied by cabbage or potatoes. My sister and my brother-in-law came to visit us recently and brought us two essential ingredients: bacalhau and broa (a special kind of cornbread). It&#39;s possible to find *bacalhau* in Denmark, but *broa* is nearly impossible, I&#39;d say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagliatelle Bolognese</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I make bolognese sauce, I usually use my own recipe that is probably miles away from the real deal. I call it bolognese because it basically has minced meat and tomato sauce. I&#39;ve looked at recipes of &#34;real&#34; bolognese and they generally include celery and carrot. When I realized that &#34;Pantagruel&#39;s&#34; recipe included those ingredients, I decided to give it a try it. The taste was definitely different from what I had ever tasted and I do hope to do justice to the original Italian recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Fricassee</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-10-chicken-fricassee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 22:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-10-chicken-fricassee/</guid>
      <description>I had never had Chicken Fricassee until now. Not that there&#39;s anything special about the way the chicken is cooked, but the sauce was extraordinary. The butter, the bits of chicken that are left behind and the mushrooms are brought together by the egg yolks resulting in a creamy and tasty sauce. I used a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34;.Ingredients (4 servings) 1 carved chicken or some whole legs and thighs 2 tablespoons butter 1 heaped teaspoon of flour 100g (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine-Braised Beef with Garlic Butter Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 22:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>This recipe resulted in a flavorful braised beef. It&#39;s quite simple to make although it takes nearly 2 hours to cook. The recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;. As for the garlic and parsley butter, it&#39;s a family recipe and it&#39;s incredibly good. In potatoes, on top of a steak, it doesn&#39;t matter. It&#39;s just good.Ingredients (6 servings)For the Braised Beef:
 1kg stewing beef  2 medium onions 2 red peppers  3 tomatoes  2 garlic cloves 1 bay leaf bunch fresh parsley 3dl (1 1/4 cups) white wine 1 tablespoon vinegar 1dl (1/3 cup) olive oil bacon, salt, pepper q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chouriço Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 16:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</guid>
      <description>Chouriço Bread, or Pão com Chouriço as we call it, is a treat you can find in Portuguese markets and fairs. It&#39;s usually baked in a trailer with wood fired ovens. You can also find it year-round in supermarkets, cafes or, more specifically, in Lisbon at Merendeira. There are even places that serve not only chouriço bread, but dried codfish bread, black pudding bread and pork rind bread. Good stuff. The recipe for the bread dough can also be used for baking regular bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion Sauce Steaks</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-20-onion-sauce-steaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 10:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-20-onion-sauce-steaks/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is another Portuguese classic. We call it Bifes de Cebolada and you can probably find it in any traditional Portuguese restaurant. I used a recipe from Culinária Portuguesa. This was the first time that I made it in Denmark because until now, I couldn&#39;t seem to find steaks with the right thickness. I didn&#39;t think twice when I actually found them. The sweetness of the onions brings out your gluttonous self and you just can&#39;t stop eating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John&#39;s Tuna Pasta</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 14:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;m sharing a very easy recipe for pasta. A friend from college came up with it. We used to cook this all the time because it&#39;s cheap and very tasty. And you can also add sweet corn if you like it.Ingredients (2 servings) 1 medium onion 2 garlic cloves 200g (7oz) sliced fresh mushrooms 2 cans of tuna (300g/10oz) 125mL (1/2 cup) of cream parsley for garnish, spaghetti, nutmeg, salt, olive oil, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coriander and Cumin Fried Pork</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-29-coriander-and-cumin-fried-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 15:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-06-29-coriander-and-cumin-fried-pork/</guid>
      <description>I cook this all the time. It&#39;s quick and easy. There are several variations of this recipe in Portugal depending on the region you come from. Where I&#39;m from we call it *Fritada*but, for instance, in the North of Portugal they call it *Rojões*. I served it with rice but a more traditional way would be to top it with chopped pickles and serve it with fries. Unfortunately, I can&#39;t seem to find the right kind of pickles here in Denmark (an assortment of cauliflower, carrots and cucumber).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Chicken</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-28-roast-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and I&#39;ve used it several times already. It turns out great every time and it&#39;s super simple to prepare. However, this was the first time that I used a free range chicken and the difference was astonishing - the meat was tastier and the sauce left in the pan was better as well. As a side note, although you start by covering the chicken with bacon, you remove it by the end of the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Pizza Dough</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 09:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-21-milk-pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>I really wanted pizza the other day and since Pantagruel had a recipe for a milk pizza dough, it was the perfect opportunity to give it a try. And it was awesome. The crust was crispy and we picked a good mixture of toppings: mozzarella, feta cheese, olives, sweet pepper and onions. As for the sauce, I tried one from Pantagruel as well, but it was too sweet. I ended up using one from Jamie at Home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Steak with Baked Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 22:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Pan Fried Steak is a Portuguese classic. I cook this at least once every other week and it never fails me. In Portugal, you can find this in almost every restaurant and it&#39;s usually accompanied by french fries, rice and a fried egg. This is my mum&#39;s recipe. As for the baked mashed potatoes, the recipe comes from Pantagruel and they were creamy with an added outside crunch.Ingredients (8-10 tarts)For the Steaks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange &amp; Ginger Chicken Thighs</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 22:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-06-orange-ginger-chicken-thighs/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe comes from Pantagruel and this was the first time that I gave it a try. The fresh ginger got my attention, but I have to say that it doesn&#39;t sound, or taste, very Portuguese. Nonetheless, it was very tasty and the mixture of orange and ginger resulted in a remarkably fresh aroma, making this recipe perfect for a summer day.Ingredients (3 servings) 6 chicken thighs and/or whole legs 1dl white wine 1 tablespoon vegetable oil 1/2 tablespoon fresh grated ginger zest 1 orange fresh mint leaves salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Leg of Lamb</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 14:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-04-28-easter-leg-of-lamb/</guid>
      <description>There is nothing Eastery about this recipe, except for the fact that in Portugal people tend to have lamb or baby goat for Easter lunch. I don&#39;t think that it is as traditional as it is to have dried codfish for Christmas, for instance. But if you ask someone what they usually eat on Easter Sunday they would probably answer lamb. It&#39;s a simple recipe with and abundance of flavors and, as the majority of roasts, ideal for the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 20:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is a Portuguese classic, just like the Chicken Stew I shared before. It&#39;s from Pantagruel, and it takes about three hours to cook so it&#39;s probably a good weekend recipe. When adding the carrots and shallots, you can also add potatoes, hence avoiding the need to cook a side dish. I didn&#39;t add the potatoes to the pot. Instead, I accompanied the beef stew with roasted potatoes (recipe to come).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Belly Roast</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-10-pork-belly-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 14:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-10-pork-belly-roast/</guid>
      <description>In kind of an homage to Denmark, I will share a recipe my favorite danish dish. You can find it in the prepared food section in the supermarkets all year long, but it&#39;s also a traditional Christmas dish. I used a Jamie Oliver recipe) which I think is pretty similar to the ones you can find here in Denmark.Ingredients (6 servings) 1,5kg (3.5 pounds) pork belly  2 onions 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 bulb of garlic salt, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stew</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 15:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-03-chicken-stew/</guid>
      <description>And now another recipe from Pantagruel. This was the first time that I tried this recipe, although I feel like I&#39;ve eaten this dish numerous times before. It reminds me of the chicken stew that used to be served at my university&#39;s dining hall. A better version of it for sure. When defining &#34;comfort food&#34; this dish should definitely be included. However, it takes a long time to cook so you should try it during the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant Gratin</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-14-eggplant-gratin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 12:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-02-14-eggplant-gratin/</guid>
      <description>The first time I tried eggplant gratin was at my mother-in-law&#39;s house. And yesterday I decided to give it a try on my own. I&#39;m not sure that the recipe that I came up with is an accurate replica but it tasted surprisingly good! The husband even said &#34;This actually tastes good, right?&#34; with a very confused look on his face. High praise. Every time I try to reproduce one of his mothers recipe I always get this gem &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mustard Pork Tenderloin</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-31-mustard-pork-tenderloin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 12:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-31-mustard-pork-tenderloin/</guid>
      <description>And now a recipe from Pantagruel. It&#39;s called &#34;Lombo de porco assado com mostarda&#34;. As per usual, there&amp;rsquo;s no mention of the oven temperature or cooking time. But it worked out great! The mustard complements the pork quite well. And here is a picture from Pantagruel of the pork cuts for the cook that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know them yet.
Ingredients (2-3 servings) 1 pork tenderloin (500g or 1lb) 3 tablespoons Dijon mustard 1 tablespoon vinegar salt, white wine q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpeas Salad</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-24-chickpeas-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 15:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-24-chickpeas-salad/</guid>
      <description>When you don&#39;t have time or patience to come up with something to cook this recipe is probably the answer to your problems. Super easy to make and it only takes the time that the eggs need do cook. And I don&#39;t know about you, but I always have these ingredients in my pantry. Win win win. Ingredients (3 servings) 2 cans of chickpeas 1 can of tuna in oil (140g or 5oz) 1 small red onion 2 eggs parsley, olive oil, vinegar, salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkey Steaks with Cream Sauce and Cabbage Rice</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-21-turkey-steaks-with-cream-sauce-and-cabbage-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 18:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-01-21-turkey-steaks-with-cream-sauce-and-cabbage-rice/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple meal but very tasty. I sometimes make the turkey steaks during the week with broccoli or some other vegetable, but because today is Saturday let&#39;s load up on carbs! No source for the recipe. It&#39;s just one of those things that I have eaten all my life. My mum actually makes this rice for special occasions because it&#39;s incredibly tasty.Ingredients (2 servings)Turkey Steaks</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
