<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beef on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/beef/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beef on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 18:36:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/beef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tagliatelle Bolognese</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 18:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-10-03-tagliatelle-bolognese/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I make bolognese sauce, I usually use my own recipe that is probably miles away from the real deal. I call it bolognese because it basically has minced meat and tomato sauce. I&#39;ve looked at recipes of &#34;real&#34; bolognese and they generally include celery and carrot. When I realized that &#34;Pantagruel&#39;s&#34; recipe included those ingredients, I decided to give it a try it. The taste was definitely different from what I had ever tasted and I do hope to do justice to the original Italian recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine-Braised Beef with Garlic Butter Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 22:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-07-wine-braised-beef-with-garlic-butter-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>This recipe resulted in a flavorful braised beef. It&#39;s quite simple to make although it takes nearly 2 hours to cook. The recipe is from &#34;Culinária Portuguesa&#34;. As for the garlic and parsley butter, it&#39;s a family recipe and it&#39;s incredibly good. In potatoes, on top of a steak, it doesn&#39;t matter. It&#39;s just good.Ingredients (6 servings)For the Braised Beef:
 1kg stewing beef  2 medium onions 2 red peppers  3 tomatoes  2 garlic cloves 1 bay leaf bunch fresh parsley 3dl (1 1/4 cups) white wine 1 tablespoon vinegar 1dl (1/3 cup) olive oil bacon, salt, pepper q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion Sauce Steaks</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-20-onion-sauce-steaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 10:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-07-20-onion-sauce-steaks/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is another Portuguese classic. We call it Bifes de Cebolada and you can probably find it in any traditional Portuguese restaurant. I used a recipe from Culinária Portuguesa. This was the first time that I made it in Denmark because until now, I couldn&#39;t seem to find steaks with the right thickness. I didn&#39;t think twice when I actually found them. The sweetness of the onions brings out your gluttonous self and you just can&#39;t stop eating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Steak with Baked Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 22:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-13-fried-steak-with-baked-mashed-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Pan Fried Steak is a Portuguese classic. I cook this at least once every other week and it never fails me. In Portugal, you can find this in almost every restaurant and it&#39;s usually accompanied by french fries, rice and a fried egg. This is my mum&#39;s recipe. As for the baked mashed potatoes, the recipe comes from Pantagruel and they were creamy with an added outside crunch.Ingredients (8-10 tarts)For the Steaks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 20:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-17-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s recipe is a Portuguese classic, just like the Chicken Stew I shared before. It&#39;s from Pantagruel, and it takes about three hours to cook so it&#39;s probably a good weekend recipe. When adding the carrots and shallots, you can also add potatoes, hence avoiding the need to cook a side dish. I didn&#39;t add the potatoes to the pot. Instead, I accompanied the beef stew with roasted potatoes (recipe to come).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
