<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tuna on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/tuna/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tuna on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 14:27:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/tags/tuna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>John&#39;s Tuna Pasta</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 14:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-07-06-johns-tuna-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;m sharing a very easy recipe for pasta. A friend from college came up with it. We used to cook this all the time because it&#39;s cheap and very tasty. And you can also add sweet corn if you like it.Ingredients (2 servings) 1 medium onion 2 garlic cloves 200g (7oz) sliced fresh mushrooms 2 cans of tuna (300g/10oz) 125mL (1/2 cup) of cream parsley for garnish, spaghetti, nutmeg, salt, olive oil, pepper, q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggplant Gratin</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-14-eggplant-gratin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 12:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-02-14-eggplant-gratin/</guid>
      <description>The first time I tried eggplant gratin was at my mother-in-law&#39;s house. And yesterday I decided to give it a try on my own. I&#39;m not sure that the recipe that I came up with is an accurate replica but it tasted surprisingly good! The husband even said &#34;This actually tastes good, right?&#34; with a very confused look on his face. High praise. Every time I try to reproduce one of his mothers recipe I always get this gem &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chickpeas Salad</title>
      <link>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-01-24-chickpeas-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 15:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.punchedpotatoes.com/recipes/2012-01-24-chickpeas-salad/</guid>
      <description>When you don&#39;t have time or patience to come up with something to cook this recipe is probably the answer to your problems. Super easy to make and it only takes the time that the eggs need do cook. And I don&#39;t know about you, but I always have these ingredients in my pantry. Win win win. Ingredients (3 servings) 2 cans of chickpeas 1 can of tuna in oil (140g or 5oz) 1 small red onion 2 eggs parsley, olive oil, vinegar, salt q.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
