<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bread on Punched Potatoes</title>
    <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/bread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bread on Punched Potatoes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:46:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/tags/bread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread II</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2013-03-30-easter-bread-ii/</guid>
      <description>I hope you&#39;re having a nice Easter. Last year I shared a recipe from &#34;Pantagruel&#34; for a traditional Portuguese Easter bread, but I completely failed its presentation. So this year I decided to try a new recipe and this time from &#34;Cozinha Tradicional Portuguesa&#34;. And I&#39;m glad I decided to give it a try because I actually prefer this version. The egg in the middle is completely optional. I&amp;rsquo;ve never in my life ate the boiled egg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic White Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-26-basic-white-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 13:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-26-basic-white-bread/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with a bread recipe for two months now. Since we only eat bread on our cheat day (we&#39;re on paleo), it took a while to get it to where I wanted it to. Bread in Denmark is remarkably different from the bread in Portugal and we find ourselves craving for something authentic, from time to time. A few years ago, my dad gave me a recipe for bread that could be tweaked to what I was looking for in a loaf of bread, with a range of possible percentages for flour and yeast instead of quantities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broas do Bolinho</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 14:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-11-12-broas-do-bolinho/</guid>
      <description>Now this is a first. I couldn&#39;t find an appropriate title in English for this post so there you go, good old Portuguese. We don&#39;t really celebrate Halloween in Portugal. Instead, on the 1st of November, children wake up early in the morning and go door-to-door asking for Bolinho or Pão-por-Deus - basically they get treats that can be in the form of these rolls I&#39;m sharing today, chocolates, money or even walnuts/chestnuts if you&#39;re terribly unlucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chouriço Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 16:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-08-03-chourico-bread/</guid>
      <description>Chouriço Bread, or Pão com Chouriço as we call it, is a treat you can find in Portuguese markets and fairs. It&#39;s usually baked in a trailer with wood fired ovens. You can also find it year-round in supermarkets, cafes or, more specifically, in Lisbon at Merendeira. There are even places that serve not only chouriço bread, but dried codfish bread, black pudding bread and pork rind bread. Good stuff. The recipe for the bread dough can also be used for baking regular bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 19:37:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-05-01-easter-bread/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the Easter topic, here is a recipe for a traditional Easter bread called *&#34;Folar&#34;*, from Pantagruel. The presentation doesn&#39;t exactly match what you would find in Portugal, but the taste sure does. The traditional presentation includes a baked egg in the middle of the bread (that we actually don&#39;t like). And I happened to forgot to brush the bread with egg yolk. :)Ingredients (2 loaves) 475g (4 cups) flour 190g (6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk Bread</title>
      <link>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 10:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paposeco.github.io/punchedpotatoes/recipes/2012-03-13-milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;ll be sharing a recipe from Pantagruel of a common bread substitute for breakfast or a mid-afternoon snack. I don&#39;t have a mixer, so I just did everything by hand, but if you have a mixer it should be a lot easier. The recipe only asks for a small amount of sugar, but it makes all the difference. They should be soft and fluffy.Ingredients (8-10 buns) 300g (2 1/2 cups) flour 70g (1/3 cup) sugar  25g (0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
